American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIg. 1887-1891 APS.Archives.IIg APS.Archives.IIg
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the President and fellow members of the American Philosophical Society., May 4, 1888; 8" x 12 1/2"; Haupt, Lewis M. (Lewis Muhlenberg), b. 1844
    [Philadelphia], 5 pp. and endorsement. Dr.D. Remarks made upon receipt of Magellanic medal. Printed in Pro., XXV, 155-157.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s Scribner's sons, May 4, 1888; 8x5; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Phila., L.S. 1p. Copy. Order for set of Encyclopaedia britannica Refers to Henry Phillips
  - Memorandum pertaining to receipt of Society's publication, May 4, 1888; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Riley, Charles V. (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    Phila., D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 5, 1888; 8x5; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for the papers. Concerning the Magellanic medal.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 5, 1888; 8x5; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 2p.,end.by E[lla] M[orison]. Asking for information about publication
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 5, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Rawson, Rawson William, Sir, 1812-1899
    [Eng.], A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning a congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 6, 1888; 5x3; Claypole, E. W. (Edward Waller), 1835-1901
    Akron, A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add., end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 7, 1888; 9-1/2x5-1/2; Ingham, William A. (William Armstrong), 1827-1913
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Says he cannot meet the Hall committee on Wednesday.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 7, 1888; 8x5; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting. Concerning the manuscript he left at the Society's rooms, and Phillips' message. On same sheet is copy of letter from H. Phillips to W.McKean, May 8, 1888.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 7, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Real Academia de la Historia
    Madrid, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:Pedro de Madrazo. 1p.and end. Partly in Spanish. Thanks for reports on Volapük. D.G. Brinton, Henry Phillips, and M.B.Snyder are mentioned.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 7, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Says he cannot attend meeting of Hall committee at hour named.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 7, 1888; 8x5; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden,N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends his copy of The Critic. Refers to [W.V.?] McKean.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 7, 1888; 8x5; Sprague, Charles E. (Charles Ezra), 1842-1912
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Concerning universal languages, specifically Volapük and [G.] Bauer's Spelin.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 8, 1888; 8x5; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Concerning [J.] Booth. Refers to [F.] Fraley.
  - Letter to W[illiam] V.McKean, May 8, 1888; 5x8; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    L.S.in another hand. 1p. Copy. Concerning the note in question. Refers to the Magellanic medal, and to [L.] Haupt. On same sheet as letter from W.McKean to H.Phillips, May 7, 1888.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], May 9, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Colorado Scientific Society
    Denver, A.L.S.:R[ichard] C.Hills,president. 1p., end. Concerning a congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 9, 1888; 3x5; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Says he is coming on the 18th with his friend D.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 9, 1888; 8x5; Reynolds, Henry Lee
    Wash.,D.C., A.LS. 2p. Concerning his paper.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 10, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S.in 3rd P. 1p.,end. Says that he cannot attend meeting of Council.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 10, 1888; 9-1/2x7; Mooney, James, 1861-1921
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p.and add.,and 2p.memo. Offers Society paper on Funeral customs of Ireland. Memo is a summary of contents.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, May 11, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Georgia Historical Society
    Savannah, A.L.S.:R[obert] Falligant,secretary. 1p., end. Concerning Volapük.
  - Letter to Frederic[k] Fraley, May 12, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Haverford College
    Haverford college, A.L.S.:Isaac Sharpless. 1p.,end. Declines to co-operate on an international congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], May 15, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    University of Edinburgh, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning a congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 15, 1888; 3-3/4X5-1/2; Königlich Sächsische Gesellschaft der Wissenschaften zu Leipzig
    Leipzig, A.L.S.: Dr. Förstemann, Archivist. 1p., end. and add. Concerns Copy of Proceedings, No.119.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 15, 1888; 10x8; Sampson, Murdock & Co.
    Boston, L. 1p.,end.,and end. Asking for Boston directory.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 16, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Kongelige Danske videnskabernes selskab
    Copenhagen, L.S.: H[ieronymus] G[eorg] Zeuthen 1p., end. Cannot participate in formation of an international language.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 17, 1888; 8x5; Reynolds, Henry Lee
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning illustrations for his paper.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], May 21, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Engineers Club of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.:Howard Murphy,secretary. 1p.,end., and end. Concerning the circular of March 12.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 22, 1888; 9-1/2x7; Mooney, James, 1861-1921
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Concerning his paper on Funeral customs of Ireland. Refers to H.Phillips. [G.F.] Barker is mentioned in the endorsement.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 23, 1888; 8x5; Townsend, Joseph B., ca. 1821-1896
    A.L.S. 1p.,end.,and end. Letter of introduction for Wm.Wirt Henry
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Fraley, May 23, 1888; 8x5; Winthrop, Robert Charles, 1809-1894
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p.,end.,and end. Concerning a congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 24, 1888; 9-1/2x5-1/2; G. & B. Westermann Brothers
    New York, L. 2p.,end. Asking for list of the works of Joseph Leidy published by Society.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Fraley, May 24, 1888; Wyoming Historical and Geological Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 30, 1888; 8-1/2x5; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends receipt.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 1, 1888; 9-1/2x5-1/2; Henry, William Wirt, 1831-1900
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S. 1p.,end.,and add.,end. Asking for correspondence between Franklin and P.Henry. FILM54-56 FRAME235
  - Note to [Henry] Phillips, June 3, 1888; 8x6; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    A.N.in 3rd P.S. 1p. Asking him to call a meeting of publication committee. Refers to [P.] DuBois and [S.] Wagner.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], June 4, 1888; 8x5; Abbot, Henry L.
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Offers his course of lectures on coast defense to the Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 4, 1888; 8x5-1/2; Foote, Albert E., 1846-1895
    [Phila.], L.S. 1p.,end.,and end. Order for publications. FILM 403 FRAME 101
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., June 4, 1888; 8x5; Royal Meteorological Society (Great Britain)
    [London], A.L.S.: William Marriott, Assistant Secretary. 1p., end. Cannot participate in proposed congress on universal language.
  - Letter to W[illia]m Wirt Henry; Phila., June 5, 1888; 5x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Fragment of L. 1p.,end. Copy? Concerning correspondence between Franklin and P.Henry. FILM 54-66 FRAME 234
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 5, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Cambridge Philological Society
    Cambridge, [Eng.] A.L.S.: John Pick, President. 1p., end. Cannot attend congress on universal language.
  - Letter to W[illia]m Wirt Henry, June 6, 1888; 6x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., L. 1p. Copy? Concerning correspondence between Franklin and P.Henry. FILM 54-66 FRAME 233
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 6, 1888; 10-1/2x8; American folk-lore society
    Cambridge, Mass., Typed L.S.:William Wells Newell. 1p.and end. Concerning Society's subscription to the folk-lore society's Journal.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 6, 1888; 3x5; Chase, Thomas Lincoln, 1831-1896
    Providence, R.I., A.L.on postal card S. 1p., end.,and add. Concerning his address.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 6, 1888; 8x5-1/2; Foote, Albert E., 1846-1895
    [Phila.], L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning publication. FILM 403 FRAME 102
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Leslie [J.Peter Lesley], June 8, 1888; 10x8; Peale, A.C. (Albert Charles), 1849-1914
    Wash.,D.C., Typed L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for obituary of [F.V.] Hayden.
  - Telegram to Henry Phillips, June 8, 1888; 5-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., Telegram S.:S[amuel] P.Langley,secretary. 1p.,end.,and end.,and add. Copy. Asking for publications.
  - Letter to Ella Morison, June 9, 1888; 9-1/2x5-1/2; Henry, William Wirt, 1831-1900
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S. 1p.,end.,and add.,end. Concerning correspondence between Franklin and P.Henry. FILM 54-66 FRAME 232
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 9, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Williams, H.
    New York, L.S. 1p.,end.by E[lla] M[orison], and calling card. Asking for publications.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, June 11, 1888; 8x5; Grant, F. E.
    New York, L.S. 2p. Asking for [T.] Nuttall's work on the flora of Arkansas.
  - Letter to [F.E. Grant, New York], June 12, 1888; 5x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Dr.of L. 1p. Concerning [T.] Nuttall's work on the flora of Arkansas.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 12, 1888; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Bataafsch Genootschap der Proefondervindelijke Wijsbegeerte (Rotterdam, Netherlands)
    Rotterdam, L.S.: G.J.W. Bremer. 1p., end. Declines invitation to attend congress on universal language.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, June 13, 1888; 8x5; Hale, Horatio, 1817-1896
    Clinton, Canada, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning an article of his for The Critic, on an international language. Refers to Volapük.
  - Letter to J. Sergeant Price, June 14, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Harris, Robert P. (Robert Patterson), 1822-1899
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end.by [Henry] Phillips. Enc. wanting. Sends dues. Offers resignation from Society. (On back of letter are notations of no apparent significance).
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, June 15, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asking that bearer of his note be permitted to examine Transactions of Royal Society.
  - Letter to Miss Morrison [Ella Morison], June 16, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Barker, George F. (George Frederick), 1835-1910
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Returns letters from [J.] Mooney and T. Williams. Concerning J.Cattell.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 16, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Royal Numismatic Society (Great Britain)
    A.L.S.:John Evans. 2p.,end.,and end. Concerning a congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to [Frederick Fraley], June 16, 1888; 8x5; Philological Society (Great Britain)
    London, A.L.S.: F[rederick] J.F[urnivall]. 2p., end.by E[lla] M[orison]. Concerning a congress for a universal language. Refers to A.J.Ellis.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 18, 1888; 10-1/2x5-1/2; Sproull, William O., b. 1848
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Asking for report on Volapük.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 19, 1888; 8x5; Smith, Edgar Fahs, 1854-1928
    Springfield, Ohio, A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Offers paper on gases for publication.
  - Letter to E[lla] Morison, June 22, 1888; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Note of introduction. Name illegible.
  - Letter to Miss Morrison [Ella Morison], June 22, 1888; 7x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Asking for names and addresses of members elected since January.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., June 22, 1888; 10-1/2x8-1/4; South African Philosophical Society
    Cape Town, Printed L. filled in in MS.,and S.: Robt. Thos. Pett, General Secretary. 1p. and add., end. Mutilated. Acknowledges receipt of report on Volapük.
  - Letter to Prof. Edgar F.Smith, June 23, 1888; 8x5; Morison, Ella M.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Copy. Concerning the disposition of his paper on gases. Refers to H.Phillips.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S. Melbourne, June 28, 1888; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Royal Society of Victoria (Melbourne, Vic.)
    A.L.S.: John James Wild. 4p., end. Sends receipt for publications. Sends own Proceedings. Discusses universal language. Refers to "Challenger Expedition."
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, June 29, 1888; 11x8; Georgia Historical Society
    Savannah, A.L.S.:R[obert] Falligant, secretary. 1p., end. Enc. Concerning appointment of A.Lawton as delegate to congress on a universal language. Enclosure is a newspaper clipping relative to his appointment.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 30, 1888; 10x8; Thomas, S. W.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. Asking for publications on universal languages.
  - Memorandum, July 2, 1888; 5x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.in the hand of Ella Morison. 1p. Concerning the Franklin manuscripts and [R.H.] Lee papers. Refers to [F.] Fraley. On same sheet as letter from F.Fraley to [Ella Morison], July 2, 1888. FILM 54-66 FRAME 236
  - Letter to Miss E.Morrison [Ella Morison], July 2, 1888; 5x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Approves of what she proposes in regard to the papers. On same sheet is [APS] Memorandum, July 2, 1888.
  - Letter to Ella Morison, July 5, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Thomas, S. W.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for reports on Volapük.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 6, 1888; 8x5; Turton, S. D.
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 2p.,end.,and end. Asking for information about Volapük.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], July 7, 1888; 8x5; Philological Society (Great Britain)
    London, A.L.S.:F[rederick] J.Furnivall. 2p.,end. Concerning a congress for a universal language. Refers to A.J.Ellis.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 9, 1888; 8x5; Turton, S. D.
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 3p.,end. Enc.wanting. Concerning Volapuk. Offers suggestions for a universal language.
  - Letter to Ella Morrison [Morison], July 10, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    A.L.S. 1P.,end. Concerning report of centennial banquet of Pennsylvania historical society. Refers to F.D.Stone.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], July 10, 1888; 11-1/4x9; International Congress of Americanists (7th: 1888: Berlin, Germany)
    Berlin, L.S.: [Wilhelm] Reiss. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends program of congress.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., July 12, 1888; 8x5; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Calcutta, L.S.: H.M. Percival, Honorary Secretary. 2p., end. Concerns report on establishment of universal language. Cannot send a delegate to proposed congress.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 12, 1888; 8x5; Randolph, Sarah N. (Sarah Nicholas), 1839-1892
    Keswick, Va., A.L.S. 2p.and end. Asking for publication. Concerning T. Jefferson. FILM 199 FRAME 723
  - Letter to Sarah N.Randolph, July 14, 1888; 8x5; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Dr.of L. 1p. Concerning price of publication.
  - Bill for lithographing of plate, July 14, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Sheppard, Edwin L., d. 1904
    Phila., D. 1p.,end.by E[dward] D.Cope.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 16, 1888; 8x5; New York Public Library
    A.L.S.:Wilberforce Eames. 1p.,end. Enc. wanting. Concerning correction of manuscript title of J.Rumsey's work on the steam engine. Refers to W.Sargent.
  - Letter to Miss Morrison [Ella Morison], July 19, 1888; 8x5; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    A.L.in 3rd P.S. 1p.and add. Enc.wanting Asking for favor in regard to enclosed paper.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 20, 1888; 3x5; Molee, Elias, b. 1845
    Bristol, Dakota [territory], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Asking for report on Volapük.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 26, 1888; 9-1/2x8; Mooney, James, 1861-1921
    Cherokee, N.C., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning his manuscript.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 27, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Naturforschende gesellschaft zu Freiburg i. B.
    Baden, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:A.Gruber. 1p.,end. In German. Order for publications.
  - Letter to H.M. Phillips [Henry Phillips], July 29, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Ocean Beach, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the matter of the books.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Aug. 3, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Worrall, Harvey
    Topeka, A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Asking for report on Volapük.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 7, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], L.S.in another hand? 1p.and add.,end. Asking for return of invitation to [international] congress [of geologists].
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Aug. 10, 1888; 7-1/4x4-1/2; University of Edinburgh
    Edinburgh, A.L.S.: J. Kirkpatrick, Secy. 1p., end., and end. Cannot participate in proposed congress on universal language.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 17, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Woodward, Charles Lowell, 1832?-1903
    New York, L.in 3rd P. 1p.,end. Asking for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Aug. 19, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Horsford, Eben Norton, 1818-1893
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Asking him to send the book to the Library company.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 20, 1888; 8x5; Pratt, L.
    Clarks, Neb., A.L.S. 3p.,end. Concerning spelling reform.
  - Letter to Edwin Sheppard, Aug. 21, 1888; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    West Falmouth, Mass., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning his bill. Asking him to write to [J.S.] Price for the money.
  - Letter to J[ames] G.Barnwell, Aug. 21, 1888; 8x5; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Dr.of L.S.:Henry Phillips,secretary. 2p. Concerning [E.N.] Horsford's book on Discovery of America by the Norsemen as gift for his library.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], Aug. 22, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Worrall, Harvey
    Topeka, A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting. Asking for information about universal languages.
  - [Upon the advantages of a universal language], Aug. 22, 1888; Steiner, P.
    A.D.S. 6p. Lecture on the benefits of a universal language, given before the A.P.S. (?), with corrections and amendments in pencil.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Aug. 23, 1888; 8x4; Philadelphia. Post office
    Phila., L.S.:William F.Harrity,postmaster. 1p. Enc. Postal matter. Enclosure is a mutilated wrapper off a package.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 23, 1888; 8x5; Library Company of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.:James G.Barnwell,librarian. 1p.,end.by E[lla] M[orison]. Asking for book on Discovery of America by the Norsemen, for his library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 24, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Woman's journal (Boston, Mass.: 1870)
    Boston, L. 2p.and add. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to president of American philosophical & philological society [Frederick Fraley], Aug. 24, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Hoss, George Washington, 1824-1906
    Baldwin, Ind., A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Enc.wanting. Concerning spelling reform.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Aug. 28, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Sheppard, Edwin L., d. 1904
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting. Asking for payment of his bill. Refers to [E.D.] Cope.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], Aug. 29, 1888; 3x5; Stout, G. W.
    Cloverdale, Kan., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Asking for information about universal languates. Refers to H.Worrall.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 2, 1888; 3x5; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    [Phila.,] A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning alterations to be made in the manuscript. Refers to R.Patterson.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 9, 1888; 8X5; Bacon, Edwin F. (Edwin Faxon), b. 1832
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. Enc. wanting. Asking for report on Volapuk. Concerning Spelin. Concerning [G.] Bauer.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 11, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment as chairman of committee to examine [J.C.] Branner's paper. Refers to [J.] Leidy.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G.Brinton, Sept. 14, 1888; 10x8; Carpenter, Richard
    Terre Haute, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Asking for report.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips?], Sept. 14, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
    New York, Fragment of Typd L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Mentioned are [James ?] Hall and [John S.?] Newberry.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 21, 1888; 5x3; Howard, Jerome B. (Jerome Bird), 1860-1923
    Cincinnati, A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add., end. Asking for report on Volapük.
  - Memorandum:, Sept. 22, 1888; 5x5; American Philosophical Society
    received from Society, [J.] Branner's paper and cuts, for committee; D.S.:W.Beaver. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 22, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asking him to give bearer [J.] Branner's paper. Refers to [J.] Leidy.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Sept. 22, 1888; 8x5; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for notices of meetings and a schedule of library hours.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 22, 1888; 9-1/2x6; Tooker, William Wallace, 1848-1917
    Sag Harbor, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for [J.] Heckewelder's work on comparative Algonkin vocabularies.
  - Letter to Prof. E[dwin] J. Houston, Sept. 24, 1888; 3x5; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Concerning purchase of books for the Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 24, 1888; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning Talcott Williams.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 25, 1888; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Enc.wanting. Concerning bills, resignations, and answers to notes. Refers to R.Thayer.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 25, 1888; 5x3; Tooker, William Wallace, 1848-1917
    Sag Harbor, N.Y., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning [J.] Heckewelder's work on comparative Algonkin vocabularies.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Sept. 25, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    A.L.S. 1p. Agrees to prepare obituary of Carvill Lewis. Concerning Mrs.Lesley.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Sept. 26, 1888; 5x8; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p. Agrees to prepare obituary of P.H.Law.
  - Letter to [Henry] P[hillips], Sept. 26?, 1888; 8x5; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., Typed L.S.1p.and end. Asking about manuscripts relating to Lewis and Clark expedition.
  - Letter to H.M. Phillips [Henry Phillips], Sept. 29, 1888; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning obituary notices. Sends letters from [J.P.] Lesley and [D.G.] Brinton. Also refers to J.Townsend's obituary of [J.P.] Wetherill.